### **RESUME**

### **BALAN. G**

Ikbalan02@gmail.com

+91-7338961060

## **Career Summary**

Geoinformatics Engineer with two years of experience in GIS, UAV Photogrammetry, LiDAR and Surveying. Skilled at Project management, Team coordination, Client handling and also worked as a Team player. Interested in learning new technologies and new platforms like Application development.

## **Technical Experience:**

Junior Coordinator in WS ATKINS, Bangalore From Feb 2020- April 2020

#### **Utility Mapping Solutions, London**

- Collecting all the responses in the given order from the outlook.
- Align the 2D maps into the Base map.
- Extracting all the utilities from the 2D maps such as Telecom, Gas, Pipeline, Electric etc
- Performed the Quality checks and finalised the output as Dwg.
- Update the responses in the OSM database as per the Clients requirements.

# **Technical Experience:**

GIS Trainee in GYOKAP Surveying and Training Institute, Chennai From Mar 2018 - Jan 2020

#### Robotic Installation for Solar Plant in Rewa, Madhya Pradesh

- Identifying the plots and blocks from the layout in Solar Plant as per the Clients requirements.
- Extracting offsets between the Solar table, height differences, ground levels etc.,
- Performed the Quality Checks and finalised the output as Spreadsheet.

#### Hotspot Analysis for Solar Plant in Telangana by Thermal Data Mapping

- Identified the hotspots in Solar Plant.
- Classification of hotspots such as Manufacturing defects, logistic defects etc.,

#### Pre-installation Survey for Solar tables Carriage Works, Perambur

- Creation of 3D sketchup for building rooftops to pre-plan installation of Solar Tables.
- Analysed shadows on the rooftop to help better positioning of panels during installation.

#### Topographical Map for Highways Like Vellore, Salem, etc.,

- Experience in handling and pre-processing of UAV data.
- Preparation of 3D based Topographical map by extracting all surface Networks.
- Generation of Contour, DEM, Longitudinal Section and Cross Section.
- Performed the Quality Checks and finalised the output as Dwg.

# **Software Proficiency**

- Arcgis, Qgis
- Google Earth
- Pix4D, Autocad
- Microstation
- Global Mapper
- Leica Mapfactory, 3D Reshaper

## **Field Experience**

- Area Calculation by Total station for Stagnated Water in KTC Nagar, Tirunelveli.
- Undergone Drone flight Experience for Building Rooftop in Carriage Works, Perambur.

## **Educational Qualifications**

#### **Academic**

• Graduated B.E Geoinformatics in Regional Campus of Anna University, Tirunelveli with 66%.

## **Schoolings**

- HSC in St. Antony's Matric Hr. Sec School, Thiruthuraipoondi with 90%.
- SSLC in St. Antony's Matric Hr. Sec School, Thiruthuraipoondi with 91%

#### **Skillset**

- Positive thinker with excellent communication skills in both written and verbal.
- Ability to lead and manage under difficult Situation.
- Easily adapt to the new environment and explore new techniques.

# **Trainings**

- Undergone Internship at Mail Soft Solutions Pvt Ltd in Guindy, Chennai.
- Undergone industrial training in Indian Meteorological Department, Chennai.
- Undergone Internship at Mapspace Consultants, Chennai.

# **Sports**

- Winner of cricket in the inter college tournament (2016-2017).
- Runner of Hockey in the inter college tournament.(2016-2017).
- Winner of Swimming in the intra college tournament for 2 years.

# **Academic Projects**

### **Project 1:**

**Soil type Mapping for agricultural lands in Munnirpallam village** of Tirunelveli using GIS. We categorize the land cover and land use fields could be analysed and import the details of the land owners and suggest that the soil is suitable of appropriate crops.

## **Project 2:**

Generation of Point Density by using Automatic Method. The tool which we develops that the point with elevation generates automation of multiple points. It interpolates with neighborhood points and it is used for making DEM analysis.

### **Personal Profile**

Father's Name : GUNASEKARAN.A

Mother's Name : INDIRANI.G

Date of Birth : 15-May-1994

Gender : Male

Addres: 1/71, North Street,

Nedumbalam(po),

Thiruthuraipoondi(Tk),

Thiruvarur(Dt).

Area of Interest : Gis, Lidar, Surveying, UAV.

## **Declaration**

I do hereby	declare	that	the	information	furnished	above	is	true	to	the	best	of	my
knowledge and belief.													_

Date:	
	(BALAN.G)
Place:	